Michael Akio

Full-Stack Engineer

Work Experience

FULL STACK ENGINEER - 08/2019 to 12/2022 **CREATE INC, Remote, U.S.**

- Participated in Decentralized applications development as a full stack developer. Used React, TypeScript, MUI and Tailwind CSS for frontend and Node.js, Express.js and PostgreSQL for backend.
- Built reusable components and responsive customer facing pages for large NFT marketplace platform including automation testing with Jest and Cypress.
- Worked on custom e-commerce SaaS platform using Vue.js with Vuex. Used Nuxt.js for SSR and Material Design, styled components as design libraries.
- Contributed to building e-commerce website by improving efficiency by 20% with GraphQL and Apollo.

MIDDLE FULL STACK (FE HEAVY) DEVELOPER - 10/2017 to 05/2019 **PINION SOFTWARE CONSULTING, Philippines**

- Implemented SEO in **Vue.js** applications and intuitive interface to achieve prominent rankings with Nuxt.js.
- Worked on building customer-facing web applications and MVP's using Vue.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL and Node.js.
- Conducted unit testing to deliver optimal browser functionality using Jest, Cypress, Mocha, and Chai.

JUNIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER - 09/2015 to 07/2016 **PINION SOFTWARE CONSULTING, Philippines**

- Converted UI designs into well organized and structured HTML/CSS compatible with modern browsers, and used open source tools and frameworks to improve the structure and maintainability of the frontend code.
- Assisted senior **frontend** developers in designing web applications and gained skills in aligning designs with client requirements.
- Used Responsive Web Design(RWD) techniques in web development, reviewed mocks, brings them to life on desktop and connected devices.

Lublin, Poland

michael.akio0216@gmail.com

Summary

A dedicated software engineer with 6+ years of professional experience in web and mobile app development.

A dedicated developer who focuses on interactive website development using modern JavaScript technologies such as React and Vue.is.

In addition, have rich experience using Next.js, Nuxt.js, GraphQL and worked extensively on Enzyme, Jest and Cypress for testing.

Passionate about working with motivated teams and getting things done.

Highlight Skills

- HTML5 / (S)CSS
- JavaScript(ES6+) / TypeScript
- React.js / Next.js
- Vue.js / Nuxt.js / Quasar/ VuePress
- Redux / Vuex
- Bootstrap 4+ / Tailwind CSS
- Material UI / Chakra UI
- Ant Design / Vuetify
- Jest / Jasmine / Mocha / Cypress
- RTL / Enzyme / Chai
- Node.js / Express / Nest.js
- REST APIs / GraphQL
- MySQL/PostgreSQL/MongoDB

Education

BA, Computer Science University of the Philippines 2011 - 2015